Finding aid for the Kasai Family papers, 1904-1972 LSC.2010.33
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Yoshihiko Kasai
  - Personal papers
    - Internment--list of camp internees, ca. 1942 (Box 110, Folder 6)
      Probably Livingston Internment Camp, in English and Japanese.
    - Internment--meeting minutes, 1942 May 4 (Box 110, Folder 7)
      "Minutes of the meeting between representatives of the Japanese internees and Consul of Spain in New Orleans, Mr. Garey "; Manuscript in Japanese
    - Internment--notebooks, ca. 1942 (Box 110, Folder 8)
    - Internment--printed material, 1932 (Box 110, Folder 9)
      Booklet, "Prisoners of War: Convention between the United States of America and other powers"
    - Internment--scrapbook, 1941-1947 (Box 110, Folder 10)
      Newspaper clippings from Japanese and English presses.
    - Internment--study report, 1942 (Box 110, Folder 11)
      "The Japanese Problem: The Answers to a Series of Questions Asked of a Nation-wide Cross-section of 3471 Adult persons" by the Polling Division Bureau of Intelligence, Office of Facts and Figures
    - Issei Interview Survey, 1965 March 21 (Box 110, Folder 12)
      Self-interview.
    - Legal documents, 1923-1927, 1933 (Box 110, Folder 13)
      Two court cases involving Y. Kasai, including booklets and Japanese newspaper clippings.
    - Miscellaneous material, 1947 December 11; n.d. (Box 110, Folder 14)
      Includes calligraphy and typescripts, "List of Recommended books on Buddhism", "The Imperial Rescript on Education", "Remittances to Japan".
    - Miscellaneous material--arranged marriage resume of Shichiko Chiku and Fumie Isomura (Box 110, Folder 15)
    - Newspaper clippings--The American Shimbun, 1938 February 12; 1938 March 26 (Box 110, Folder 16)
      In Japanese and English
    - Nishikawa divorce case, 1941 (Box 110, Folder 17)
      Yoshihiko Kawai served as court interpreter. Material in Japanese and English
    - Registration certificates and identification cards, 1917, 1930, 1943, 1945 (Box 110, Folder 18)
    - Table list of the Thomas Jefferson prizes, 1947 April 13 (Box 110, Folder 19)